DYLAN MATHER

2415 Bunya Street Newport Beach, CA 92660 (571)-481-8783 matherdy@msu.edu

Statistics Major with Minor in Data Science. Experience in guiding learning in a flipped classroom setting as well as running operations for a retail and rental shop. Volunteer experience in fraternity community service. Actively pursuing graduate programs and a career in Data Science.

EDUCATION

MICHIGAN STATE UNIVERSITY, East Lansing, Michigan

Major: Statistics, Fall 2016 - Present

- Relevant Completed Courses: Engineering Physics 1-2, Calculus 1-4, Matrix Algebra, Transitions, Probability and Statistics 1-2, Statistics for Biologists, Stochastic Processes and Applications
- Relevant Current Courses: Capstone in Statistics, Computations in Probability and Statistics

Minor: Data Science, Fall 2019-Present

- Relevant Completed Courses: Computational Modeling Tools and Techniques, Data Visualization
- Relevant Current Courses: Fundamental Data Science Methods

Study Abroad: University College Dublin, Dublin, Ireland, Summer, 2016

• Courses in sustainability in tourism

EXPERIENCE

CMSE LEARNING ASSISTANT, East Lansing, Michigan

Summer 2019-Present

- Instruct students in a flipped classroom setting
- Maintain office hours for two hours every week, and actively monitor and assist on Slack help channel
- Assisted in the transition to an online setting due to COVID-19

DELPHI HYBRID CAR RESEARCH PROJECT, East Lansing, Michigan

Spring 2017

• Engaged with Delphi Company to research and optimize the design and location of a motor generator unit in the car's engine

ISLAND PADDLEBOARD, Newport Beach, California

Summers, 2016 – 2019

- Managed retail and rental operations Scheduled appointments and travel arrangements for customers, supervisors, and managers
- Provided customer service, instruction, and maintenance

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Proficient in Python, C++, R, and Microsoft Office
- Experience in SAS and MATLAB

ADDITIONAL INTERESTS

- I enjoy working with teams to solve complex problems that have an impact on our world
- Contributed in a community service project to raise money for bringing filtered straws to Boys and Girls club in Flint, Michigan